As the first successful wallbreaker
作为第一个破壁的人
you are worthy of admiration.
你值得敬佩
As someone who has been a wallfacer for so long
做了这么久面壁者
you
你
must have had a hard time.
肯定很难吧
As for finding someone
找人这事儿
I have a way.
我有法子
Have you heard of the beacon tower?
听说过烽火台吗
Luo Ji
罗辑
There are only about 8 hours left until the ladder is fully covered.
距离天梯被完全覆盖大约只剩8小时
It is impossible to break free from the gravity directly.
直接挣脱引力是做不到的
You will have to use force to be thrown out.
只有借力被甩出去才行
Do your best
尽人事
Luo Ji
罗辑
and leave the rest to fate.
听天命吧
Wake up quickly.
快醒醒
The current air pressure is stable.
当前气压稳定
We have
是这儿
arrived.
到了
What are you thinking?
你在想什么
I'm thinking
我在想
that as soon as I put on my helmet, everything went black.
刚头盔里一片漆黑
Is this the true face of the universe?
是不是这才是宇宙的真面目
Everything that is uncertain
一切不确定
has been filtered out
都被过滤掉了
and all I can see are coordinates
只看得到数字
and numerical values.
坐标系
Is this what you hoped for?
你希望是这样的吗
I don't want this.
不希望
Why not?
为什么
Because I can't see you anymore.
那我看不见你了
Why do you have to see me?
干吗一定要看见我呀
To feel at ease.
看见你才安心
Seeing you makes me feel secure.
那你看着我的时候
I collapse when you look at me
我是不是就坍缩了
according to Dr. Ding.
按丁博士说的
You don't think that
你不会以为
collapse means disappearing, do you?
坍缩就是消失吧
Nope.
不会啊
The quantum body is still there.
量子体不是也一直在吗
Don’t worry.
别担心
I won't let anything happen to you.
我不会让你有事的
I feel like I've dreamed of this scene before.
我好像梦到过这个场景
Drifting in space?
飘在太空
No.
不
Drifting in the sea.
漂在海里
When I graduated, I felt like a fish thrown into the ocean
毕业时 觉得自己像鱼被丢进了大海
not knowing where to go.
不知道该去哪
But now
但现在
I've never been so clear.
从没这么清楚过
What do you understand now?
你现在清楚什么
There is oxygen here.
这有氧气
You can take off your helmet.
头盔可以卸了
Reminder. The helmet has been removed.
提示头盔已摘除
Do you understand what we need to do?
清楚我们要做什么呀
First, go to the spindle console
先去主轴操作台
and release the nanofilaments
释放纳米丝
to make the Yellow River station rise.
让黄河站升高
Right?
对吧
Then
然后呢
drive the nuclear power plant that needs to fly away to its maximum.
把要飞走的那个核电站开到最大
In this way, the quantum body will rise up until
这样没多久量子体就会往上跑
the nuclear power plant takes it away.
直到核电站把它带走
While this is happening
趁这个时间我们赶紧回来
let's hurry back here.
回这里
Am I right?
没错吧
No.
不行
No no no
不行不行
this won't work.
这么搞不了
What's wrong?
怎么了
This place is worse than the outer ring.
这儿比外环还糟
We can't even open the backup power hatch.
备用电连舱门都开不了
How can we release the nanofilaments?
怎么可能释放纳米丝
Is the PDC misleading us?
PDC不会在坑人吧
What should we do?
那怎么办
The nuclear power plant has electricity, right?
核电站不是有电吗
But we need to release the nanofilaments before starting the nuclear power plant.
那也得先放纳米丝再运行核电站啊
Or
或者
maybe we can switch the order of operations.
调换操作顺序
Generate electricity first and then raise the Yellow River station.
先发电再让黄河站上升
But if we do that
可这样的话
can we safely return here?
我们能安全回到这里吗
I don't know.
我不知道
How long has it been?
时间过了多久
10 minutes later than expected.
比预计晚了 10分钟
Normally, the nuclear power plant would automatically disconnect when the height is detected
按理说核电站检测到高度会自动脱离的
but there is no response now.
但现在完全没反应
What about the rescue team?
救援呢
The platform can be unlocked and dispatched
平台一解锁就能出发
but we have to wait for Luo Ji to complete the final step.
但得等罗辑完成最后一步
The backup power is also running low.
备用电也快没了
We need to start the nuclear power plant quickly.
我们得赶紧启动核电站
Only short-range wireless communication is possible.
现在只有短距离可以无线通讯
We can't afford to lose contact again.
我们俩不能再失联了
The essence of the observer effect is the outflow of information.
观察者效应的本质是信息的流出
The outflow of information
信息的流出
information.
信息
What if the quantum bodies get closer?
万一量子体靠近了
Remember
你记着
you have to activate the visual enhancement mode.
你就打开视觉增强模式
Didn't they say not to use the visual enhancement?
不是说视觉增强不要碰吗
But then I suddenly realized
但我突然想到
the visual enhancement image and the data of the spacesuit
视觉增强画面和舱外服数据
are essentially our information.
本质上不就是我们的信息吗
Ding Yi said before
丁仪之前说过
We must establish a stable connection with the outside of the shielding layer
必须建立我们和屏蔽层外的稳定连接
If we combine short-range wireless
如果短距离无线
and long-distance fiber
加上长距离的光纤
we can enable the Yellow River Station to receive our information.
让黄河站能够接收到我们的信息
Are you going to use that
你是要用丁博士说的那个
quantum observer effect that Dr. Ding mentioned?
量子的观察者效应
This student is very smart.
这位同学很聪明啊
Prof. Luo is a good teacher.
罗老师教得也很好呀
This may be the only way to survive inside the quantum body.
这可能是唯一在量子体里保命的办法了
You should stay here
你还是乖乖待在这儿
and not go anywhere
哪儿也别去
understand?
知道吗
I'll stay here
我待在这儿
and wait a bit.
等一下
Why?
为什么
What are you doing?
你干什么
We can't separate.
我们不能分开
I've told you before.
我跟你说过的
Promise me.
先答应我
I understand.
我知道
I remember every word you said
你每句话我都记得
including the ones you didn't say.
包括没说出口的
You don't want me to be in danger
你不想我有危险
do you?
对吗
So someone has to do this
所以这件事总要有人做
or else we won't be able to leave.
不然我们都没法走
I'm not leaving you alone.
我不是要丢下你一个人
When the quantum body gets closer
量子体靠近之后
I won't be able to distinguish directions
我会分不清方向
so you have to be
所以你得做我的
my lighthouse.
我的灯塔
Without a location, I won't be able to come back.
没有定位我回不来
so you have to wait for me here
你要在这等我
and guide me.
帮我指引方向
Okay?
好吗
You have to come back.
你要回来
You still haven't given me what you
你还有东西没给我呢
said you would regret not giving me.
说不给会后悔的那个
Wait..
A|^r Zq^r
Did you see it?
你看到了
So, are you saying
那你是说
that you're willing?
你愿意吗
I'm still waiting for you to tell me
我还等你告诉我
what Goethe said.
歌德到底说了什么
This is
这
what you said.
这可是你说的
Don't go back on your word.
可别反悔啊
When I come back
我回来的时候
don't deceive me.
你不准骗我
As long as you're
只要你回来
coming back
你在
I'll be here.
我就在
Abnormal increase in ionizing radiation detected.
检测到电离辐射增幅异常
Abnormal increase in magnetic field strength.
磁场强度增幅异常
It came so fast.
来这么快
How are you doing?
你怎么样
It was just magnetic interference.
刚才是磁场干扰
Are you okay?
你还好吗
I'm fine.
没事
I'm fine
我没事
I've arrived at the control area of the central axis.
到中轴的控制区了
I won't disturb you anymore.
那我不打扰你了
Don't worry
别
I feel at ease when I hear your voice.
听你声音我安心些
Why are you laughing?
笑什么
Actually, I'm the same.
其实我也是
Wait a moment
等一下
Zhuang Yan
庄颜
I am here.
我在呢
What I'm doing now is..
我现在干的事儿
If I go back, you have to testify for me.
回去了可得帮我作证
It's what PDC taught me.
是PDC教我的
Would someone ask a Wallfacer that?
会有人这么问面壁者吗
Yes
对呀
This must be part of the plan.
这肯定是计划的一部分
Really?
果然
Normal operation won't work at all.
正常操作根本行不通
Just as I thought.
跟我想的一样
We have to deal with the nuclear power plant first.
得先搞核电站
Then you protect yourself.
那你保护好自己
Isn't it dangerous to operate at full power?
满功率会不会很危险啊
It's okay
没事儿
just follow the instructions.
顺着指示来就
There's no other way.
也没别的办法了
I'm starting now.
我开始了
Wait, wait, wait, wait
别别别别别
what are you doing?
搞什么
What's the matter? Luo Ji
怎么了罗辑
Luo Ji.
罗辑
Say something.
你别不说话啊
I'm worried.
我很担心
Zhuang Yan.
庄颜
I'm here. What do you want to say?
我在你说
It's nothing.
没什么
How about we
要不就
just talk?
随便聊聊呗
Now?
现在吗
When you paint
你每次上色的时候
do you prefer warm
喜欢先用暖色
or cool colors?
还是冷色
Why are you asking this?
怎么问这个啊
Anyway, there's only blue and red
反正就是只有蓝和红
so just go with your intuition.
你凭感觉就行了
Which one would you choose?
你会选哪个
Okay
好吧
if you must ask
非要问的话
then it's definitely..
那肯定是
I know.
我知道了
Yes.
对啊
Because I like
因为我喜欢
You like
你喜欢
the eyes of the sunset.
晚霞的眼睛嘛
Why are you asking this?
到底为什么问这个呀
Because
因为
you will choose right.
你会是对的
The Yellow River station's generator has been connected to the power grid and is operating normally.
黄河站发电机组并网发电正常
It has been linked to the high-altitude transfer station's power system
已接入高空中转站电力系统
The auxiliary nuclear power plant has switched to full-power operation.
副核电站切换至满功率运行
What happened?
发生什么了
The program has been updated.
检测到程序更新
In any case
反正就是
The ladder has begun the counterweight adjustment state.
天梯进入配重调节状态
You saved us.
你救了我们
The central axis main power grid equipment is operating normally.
中轴主电网设备运行正常
The distribution systems of the ring roads are responding.
各环道配电系统响应中
The ignition of the Yellow River Station's thruster is underway.
黄河站推进器点火工作
the operating orbit has been changed to detach from the auxiliary nuclear power station
运行轨道变更至副核电站脱离轨道
The hydraulic braking system is unlocked.
液压制动系统解锁
The nanofilaments are about to be released.
纳米丝即将释放
Great.
太好了
We made the right bet.
我们赌对了
As expected from a Wallfacer.
不愧是面壁者
He did it.
他做到了
Chairman.
主席
The shielding layer of the quantum body is starting to shift
量子体的屏蔽层开始偏移
The low-altitude station safety system override is complete.
低空站安全系统覆写完成
Immediately release the low-altitude station lock.
立刻解除低空站锁定
Understood.
收到
The dock platform is starting to unlock.
船坞平台开始解锁
The cabin pressure has been balanced.
舱内压力已平衡
System-wide self-test is complete.
全系统自检完成
Rescue No. 4 is ready.
救援4号准备就绪
Can you see the position of my spacesuit?
能看到我宇航服的定位吗
Come back soon.
快回来吧
Right away.
马上
I can see it.
看得到
Wait for me.
等我
Luo Ji.
罗辑
What's wrong? I'm here.
怎么了我在
The quantum body seems to be approaching
量子体好像在靠近
You have to come back quickly.
你得赶快回来
What did you say?
你说什么
Alert.
警报
The hydraulic braking system has malfunctioned.
液压制动系统发生故障
Nanofilaments cannot be released.
纳米丝无法释放
Level 1 Disaster Alert.
一级灾难警报
The nanofilaments chamber is about to break.
纳米丝轮机室即将断裂
The quantum body seems to be changing.
量子体好像在变
Can you hear me? Luo Ji.
罗辑听得到吗
Level 1 Disaster Alert
一级灾难警报
The high altitude station damaged.
高空站损毁
The nanofilaments chamber is about to break.
纳米丝轮机室即将断裂
What the hell.
什么鬼
Zhuang Yan.
庄颜
Can you hear me?
你听到了吗
Luo Ji.
罗辑
Come back quickly.
你快回来
How can we make it?
这哪回得了
The safety disintegration mode failed to activate.
安全解体模式启用失败
Both of us can't go down together.
咱俩不能都搭进去了
The main structure of the high-altitude transfer station is about to be damaged
高空中转站主结构即将损毁
I'll go up and take a look.
我上去看看
Don't be afraid.
你别怕
Wait for me.
等我
What's wrong?
怎么了
Electromagnetic disturbance detected.
检测到电磁紊乱
Can't go up anymore.
上不去了
Satellite detected.
卫星检测到
The auxiliary nuclear power station has not yet left orbit
副核电站还没到脱离轨道
but it has stopped.
但已经停了
I don't know why.
不知道为什么
Ding Yi
丁仪
How could the quantum body get stuck?
怎么量子体也能卡壳
The quantum body only moves along the magnetic field.
量子体只会随磁场移动
It's a problem with the counterweight station.
是配重站的问题
It's a problem with the engine room.
是轮机室的问题
What's going on with
轮机室
the engine room?
怎么回事
I thought the explosion only damaged the outer ring and truss.
我以为爆炸只损坏了外环和桁架
It seems that the nanofilaments can't be released normally either.
看来纳米丝也没法正常释放了
Wang Miao
汪淼
This is not the time to joke around.
这节骨眼别开玩笑
I'm not in the mood to joke around.
我哪有心情开玩笑
The tension at the Yellow River station has continued
黄河站的拉力一直在持续
and the nanofilament can withstand it
纳米丝受得住
but the engine room can't.
轮机室受不住啊
The structural material
航建材料
has a tensile stress threshold.
也有拉应力阈值
If this goes on
这么扯下去
the space ladder will fall apart.
天梯要散架了
It would be better if the ladder could disintegrate safely
要是能让天梯安全解体还好些
but the comprehensive stress on the nanofilament and engine room
但现在纳米丝和轮机室的综合受力
is likely to cause structural tearing.
恐怕会引起结构撕裂
If the high-altitude station explodes due to pressure difference
万一高空站因为气压差爆炸
Professor Luo will...
那罗教授就
Warning: The space ladder's counterweight process is forced to stop
警告天梯配重进程被迫中止
Abnormal release of nanofilaments.
纳米丝释放异常
Please have a level-two engineer go to the nanofilaments engine room
请二级工程师立即前往纳米丝轮机室
to manually troubleshoot the problem.
手动排查故障
Abnormal increase in ionizing radiation detected.
检测到电离辐射增幅异常
Abnormal increase in magnetic field intensity detected.
磁场强度增幅异常
Zhuang Yan
庄颜
can you wait for me a bit longer?
能再等下我吗
Please confirm if you are in a unsafe area.
请确认是否处于非安全区域
I can't just ignore it.
我不能不管
Otherwise we will both die here.
不然咱俩都会死在这
Do you hear me?
听到了吗
Zhuang Yan
庄颜
Current body temperature is 37.6 C.
检测到现时体温37.6℃
Heart rate is 168 beats per minute.
心跳频率每分钟168次
Please confirm if you are currently engaged in unconventional activities outside the cabin
请确认是否正在进行非常规舱外活动
and if you are in a unsafe area.
是否处于非安全区域
Alarm detected that the space suit is leaking air and losing pressure.
警报检测到舱外航天服漏气失压
Please take immediate safety measures.
请立即采取安全保障措施
Alert: oxygen remaining at 65%.
警报氧气剩余量65%
Alert: oxygen remaining at 58%.
警报氧气剩余量58%
If time could stop
如果时间能停止
just one more second
再多一秒
either we will successfully leave
要么成功离开
or
要么
the diffusion will accelerate
扩散加速
Because what he is facing
因为他面对的
is something we can't imagine.
是我们无法想象的事情